No warning. No escape.
Pompeii is a action, adventure, history film directed by Paul W. S. Anderson.
In 79 A.D., Milo, a slave turned gladiator, finds himself in a race against time to save his true love Cassia, the
beautiful daughter of a wealthy merchant who has been unwillingly betrothed to a corrupt Roman Senator.
As Mount Vesuvius erupts in a torrent of blazing lava, Milo must fight his way out of the arena
in order to save his beloved as the once magnificent Pompeii crumbles around him.
Milo, played by Kit Harington.
Cassia, played by Emily Browning.
Atticus, played by Adewale Akinnuoye-Agbaje.
Corvus, played by Kiefer Sutherland.
Aurelia, played by Carrie-Anne Moss.
Severus, played by Jared Harris.
Pompeii is a 2014 historical disaster film produced and directed by Paul W.
An international co-production between the United States, Germany and Canada, it is a fictional tale inspired
by the eruption of Mount Vesuvius in 79 AD that destroyed Pompeii, a city of the Roman Empire.
The film stars Kit Harington, Carrie-Anne Moss, Emily Browning, Adewale
Akinnuoye-Agbaje, Jessica Lucas, Jared Harris and Kiefer Sutherland.
Pompeii premiered in France, Belgium, and Russia on February 19, 2014, and was released over the course of the next day
in Argentina, Greece, Hungary, Italy and later in the United States and Canada on February 21, 2014.
This is FilmDistrict's last film before it merged with Focus Features.
The film received mixed reviews grossed $117.8 million
against a budget of $80-100 million.
The film explores themes of lava, gladiator, arena,
gladiator fight, natural disaster.
The tone is emotional.